[
    {
        "question": "Glacier is a huge mass of ice so its velocity is ...............",
        "options": [
            "More",
            "Less",
            "Average",
            "High"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "When many flows of water come together, a ............... is formed.",
        "options": [
            "Sea",
            "Oceans",
            "River",
            "Lake"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Wind is a gaseous agent of .................",
        "options": [
            "Transportation",
            "Erosion",
            "Soil movement",
            "Depiction"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Pick out odd one - Cirques, aretes, horns, gorges",
        "options": [
            "Cirques",
            "Aretes",
            "Horns",
            "Gorges"
        ],
        "answer": 4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The ............... work of the wind takes place in the area where its speed is reduced.",
        "options": [
            "Erosional",
            "Transportation",
            "Depositional"        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Eroded materials in the sea bed became fine because of ................ and hitting each other",
        "options": [
            "Reduction",
            "Waves",
            "Attrition",
            "Hydraulic action"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea waves carry out their work in the ................. areas.",
        "options": [
            "Coastal",
            "Plateau",
            "Hilly",
            "River"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Glaciers carry sediments which are called ...................",
        "options": [
            "Moraines",
            "Sheepbacks",
            "Aretes",
            "All the above"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of the glacier is ................ as compared to river.",
        "options": [
            "Fast",
            "Slow",
            "Medium",
            "High"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Alluvial fans are formed by the rivers at the ............... of the hills.",
        "options": [
            "Slopes",
            "Foothills",
            "Peaks",
            "Valleys"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "A river flows at a great speed in the ............... region. ",
        "options": [
            "Plain",
            "Valley",
            "Mountainous",
            "Plateau"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": " The river originates at a much higher ...................... from sea level.",
        "options": [
            "Altitude",
            "Attitude",
            "Longitude",
            "Peak"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The earthâ€™s surface wears away because of ................",
        "options": [
            "Transportation",
            "Depuration",
            "Erosion",
            "Ox bow lakes"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The velocity of the Jacobshavn Glacier in Greenland is ............... per day.",
        "options": [
            "1 cm",
            "1 m",
            "46 M",
            "50 M"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "............... of rocks occurs due to the hitting of the waves at the coast.",
        "options": [
            "Erosion",
            "Breaking",
            "Movement",
            "Both 1 and 2"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Landforms like flood plains and ............... are formed because of deposition sediments.",
        "options": [
            "Eskers",
            "Deltas",
            "Barchans",
            "Harms"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In regains where temperature are below freezing point, precipitation  is in the form of",
        "options": [
            "Rain",
            "Hail",
            "Snowfall",
            "Freezing rain"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Formation of ............... is the erosional work of the wind.",
        "options": [
            "Barchan",
            "Seif",
            "Sand dunes",
            "Mushroom rock"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The work of the wind is prominent in ................ region.",
        "options": [
            "Plain",
            "Desert",
            "Mountainous",
            "Hot"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The erosional work of glaciers produces landforms like ...............",
        "options": [
            "Gorges",
            "Yardangs",
            "Cirques",
            "Hamad"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    }
]